Guide to the Henry R. Luce Papers 1894-2004 (bulk, 1932-1967) MS 3014
New-York Historical Society
- Series V. Subject Name Files, 1894-1995 (bulk 1933-1967); 30.1 Linear feet
  - Subseries V.B. Name Files B, 1910-1974 (bulk 1933-1967)
    - Eddy, Sherwood, 1937-1954 (Box 118, Folder 1)
      Includes brochures and brochure proofs for "The American Seminar" and "The European Seminar," and a draft of "A Four-fold Plan for India."
    - Eden, Sir Anthony, 1940-1956 (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - Edison, Governor Charles, 1943-1961 (Box 118, Folder 1)
      Includes minutes of the meeting of the Executive Committee of the Board of Directors of the National War Fund, Inc.
    - Edmonds, Harry, 1953 (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - Eichelberger, General Robert, 1946 (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - Eiges, Sydney T., 1955 (Box 118, Folder 2)
      Includes a National Broadcasting Company (NBC) studio pass card for 1956.
    - Einaudi, Luigi, 1955 (Box 118, Folder 2)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. - Far East, 1952-1965 (Box 118, Folder 2)
      Includes memoranda titled "The Vital Interests of the USA in Asia," "Outline of Strategy for Asia," "A Republican Policy for Asia" as well as others dealing with policy in the Pacific. In addition there is a petition addressed to the President expressing opposition to the admission of the Chinese People's Republic to the United Nations. Correspondents include Charles R. Hook, and Eisenhower (copies).
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. - Birthday Dinner, 14 October 1965 (Box 118, Folder 2)
      Includes lists of names.
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. - Law, 1958 (Box 118, Folder 2)
      Includes a carbon copy of the text of the President's letter to Arthur Larson regarding the establishment of the Rule of Law Center at Duke University.
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. - National Presbyterian Church, 1957-1961 (Box 118, Folder 2)
      Includes copies of correspondence regarding the fundraising efforts for the construction of the church, and a copy of a signed statement from Eisenhower for a brochure about the project.
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. - Miscellaneous (folder 1 of 2), 1950-1952 (Box 118, Folder 3)
      Includes the pamphlet "The American Assembly," a copy of a letter from Eisenhower regarding the Engineering Center at Columbia University, correspondence and memoranda dealing with the 1952 presidential campaign, and two drafts of Eisenhower's? speeches. Also includes one original letter signed by Eisenhower.
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. - Miscellaneous (folder 2 of 2), 1953-1965 (Box 118, Folder 4)
      Includes a list of Eisenhower's appointments to the new administration, HRL's schedule for the presidential inauguration ceremonies, text of Eisenhower's foreign policy address, the pamphlet "Eisenhower's America: Notes on a Journey by a Special Correspondent of The Times," and a list of achievements of the Eisenhower presidency. Also includes an original signed letter from Eisenhower to John Cridel, and two signed letters from Mamie Eisenhower.
    - Eisenhower, Milton S., 1953-1957 (Box 118, Folder 5)
      Includes a tentative statement of objectives of the American-Korean Foundation, and the speech "Ideas at War: The Moral Conflict of Our Time."
    - Eliot, George F., 1940-1942 (Box 118, Folder 5)
    - Elizabeth II, Queen of England - 21 October 1957 Visit to New York (Box 118, Folder 5)
      Includes two souvenir programs from the luncheon given by Robert F. Wagner at the Waldorf Astoria in honor of Queen Elizabeth II and Prince Philip.
    - El-Kateb, H. E. Hassan, 1956 (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - Ellis, Hugh, 1942 (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - Elterich, Harold N., 1942-1948 (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - Emeny, Brooks, 1941-1952 (Box 118, Folder 6)
      Includes carbon copies of letters sent by Emeny to General Frank R. McCoy and Nelson A. Rockefeller, and brochures for the Newton D. Baker Lecture Fund.
    - Emmet, Jr. Christopher T., 1944 (Box 118, Folder 6)
      Includes a speech by Emily Hahn made at a United China Relief rally in Bridgeport, CT.
    - Engel, A. Ferdinand, 1956 (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - Engel, Samuel R., 1948 (Box 118, Folder 6)
      Includes a letter from Mrs. Lecomte du Nouy.
    - Engle, Paul, 1956-1959 (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - Enriques, Giovanni, 1954-1955 (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - Erhard, Ludwig, 1954-1966 (Box 118, Folder 6)
      Includes a prospectus for a monthly publication review titled "Focus: An International Forum for Economic Policy."
    - Ernst, Morris L., 1939-1965 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Espy, R. H., 1946 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Eurich, Alvin R., 1948 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Eugenides, Eugene, 1953 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Evans, Arthur, 1935 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Everitt, Sam, 1938-1951 (Box 119, Folder 1)
      Includes photographs of an unidentified road, and correspondence and memoranda on the proposed creation of The History Book Club.
    - Everett, Tom (John T.), 1951-1953 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Ewald, Henry T., 1937-1953 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Exman, Eugene, 1946-1963 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Faina, Count Carlo, 1953-1960 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Fairbank, Mrs. Kellogg, 1935 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Fairbanks, Jr. Douglas, 1951 (Box 119, Folder 2)
      Correspondence from Fairbanks consists of copies.
    - Fang, General Chen-Wu, 1936 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Faries, McIntyre, 1947-1960 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Farley, James, 1940-1955 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Farrar, John, 1938-1952 (Box 119, Folder 2)
      Includes printed materials from The League of American Writers announcing the sale of manuscripts and letters for the benefit of the Medical Bureau of the North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy, and broadsides of the newspaper column "It Makes Sense" distributed by the Committee to Defend America.
    - Fearn, Dr. Anne W., 1938 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Felici, Alfonso, 1956 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Fenn, William P., 1964 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Ferguson, Harold S., 1943 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Ferguson, Homer, 1952-1954 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Ferragamo, Salvatore, 1955 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Fey, Harold E., 1946 (Box 119, Folder 3)
    - Field, Sr. and Jr. Marshall, 1941-1964 (Box 119, Folder 3)
      Includes a draft of Field Jr.'s speech "Mass Media and Better Human Understanding."
    - Field, Robert M., 1942-1948 (Box 119, Folder 3)
      Includes a chart showing monthly disposals for the War Assets Administration.
    - Fielding, Temple, 1963 (Box 119, Folder 3)
      Includes a Danish clipping announcing HRL's appointment by the King of Denmark to be the Commander of Dannebrog.
    - Fifield, James W., 1948-1959 (Box 119, Folder 3)
      Includes a pamphlet with the sermon "Don't Manufacture Your Own Happiness" by Norman Vincent Peale.
    - Finch, E. C. K. (Kip), 1951-1955 (Box 119, Folder 3)
    - Findley, Paul, 1965 (Box 119, Folder 3)
    - Finkelstein, Louis, 1940-1963 (Box 119, Folder 4)
      Includes a preliminary announcement and invitation to the Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion in Their Relation to the Democratic Way of Life, and memoranda regarding the Institute for Religious and Social Studies.
    - Finletter, Thomas K., 1941 (Box 119, Folder 5)
    - Firesone, Harvey, 1938-1948 (Box 119, Folder 5)
    - Fisher, Samuel H., 1944 (Box 119, Folder 5)
    - Fisher, Thomas Hart, 1937-1938 (Box 119, Folder 5)
      Includes the book State House Versus Pent House: Legal Problems of the Rhode Island Race-Track Row by Zechariah Chafee, Jr.
    - Fitch, Hugh R., 1945-1955 (Box 119, Folder 5)
      Includes the poems "Christmas Ode to the United Nations" and "The Nativity" by Fitch.
    - Fitzpatrick, Teresa S., 1943 (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Flanders, Ralph E., 1943-1947 (Box 119, Folder 6)
      Includes a reprint of Flanders's article "Let's Face It."
    - Flemming, Arthur S., 1953 (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Fletcher, Harris, 1945 (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Fly, James L., 1943-1945 (Box 119, Folder 6)
      Includes a pamphlet with the address of Enders M. Voorhees before the Controllers' Institute of America.
    - Folsom, Frank, 1954-1958 (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Fon, Antonio, 1953 (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Forbes, Malcolm, 1957 (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Ford, Henry and Henry Ford II, 1943-1967 (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Ford, Lauren, 1947 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Forkner, Dr. C. E., 1942 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Fornacca, J. J., 1954 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Forrestal, James, 1942-1953 (Box 120, Folder 1)
      Includes the brochure "The James Forrestal Research Center."
    - Fosdick, Raymond B., 1956 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Fox, James, 1955 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Foy, Byron, 1940 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Fraccaroli, Arnaldo, 1954 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Francis, Clarence, 1936 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Francisco, Don, 1940 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Frank, Glenn, 1938 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Frank, Jerome N., 1943-1944 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Franklin, George S., 1951 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Frassineto, Marinetta, 1955 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Fratini, G., 1954 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Frederika, Queen of Greece, 1956-1964 (Box 120, Folder 2)
      Includes a holiday card? with a photograph of the Queen and King Paul and a photograph of their crowning ceremony?
    - Freeman, Fulton, 1965 (Box 120, Folder 2)
    - Freeman, Jr. Gaylord A., 1962-1965 (Box 120, Folder 2)
    - Friendly, Fred, 1938 (Box 120, Folder 2)
    - Fuehr, Carlos, 1939 (Box 120, Folder 2)
      Includes a postcard with the image of Allerton House on 39th Street, New York.
    - Fulbright, J. W. - Meeting with the Senate Foreign Relations Committee on 17 September 1958, 1958-1960 (Box 120, Folder 2)
      Includes an "Outline of and Procedures for Study of United States Foreign Policy Being Undertaken by the Committee on Foreign Relations, United States Senate."
    - Fummi, Giovanni, 1953-1956 (Box 120, Folder 2)
    - Funston, Keith, 1960 (Box 120, Folder 2)
    - Furst, George A., 1956 (Box 120, Folder 2)
    - Gaitskell, Sir Hugh, 1957 (Box 120, Folder 3)
    - Galassi, Ugo, 1953 (Box 120, Folder 3)
    - Gambrell, E. Smythe, 1959-1967 (Box 120, Folder 3)
    - Gannett, Frank, 1937-1938 (Box 120, Folder 3)
    - Gardner, Clinton, 1953 (Box 120, Folder 3)
    - Gardner, Hy, 1962 (Box 120, Folder 3)
    - Gardner, John W., 1956-1965 (Box 120, Folder 3)
    - Garland, Charles S., 1952-1960 (Box 120, Folder 3)
    - Garrett, Paul, 1945 (Box 120, Folder 3)
    - Garside, B. A., 1938-1951 (Box 120, Folder 4)
      Includes memoranda from the Associated Boards for Christian Colleges in China, meeting minutes of the Board of Directors of United China Relief, a United China Relief stamp, memoranda dealing with the reorganization of United China Relief, and expense and progress reports for United China Relief.
    - Gates, Artemus L. (Mr. and Mrs.), 1937-1962 (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - Geist, Walter, 1948 (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - George VI, King of England, 1939 June 8 (Box 120, Folder 5)
      Contains an invitation to a garden party to Henry and Clare Boothe Luce from the British ambassador on behalf of "Their Britannic Majesties' commands."
    - George, Walter F., 1957 (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - Gerard, James W., 1938-1947 (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - Getchell, J. Stirling, 1936 (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - Gibbs, William F., 1935-1961 (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - Gifford, Walter S., 1940 (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - Gilbert, Edwin, 1937 (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - Gilkey, Dr. Langdon, 1966 (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - Gillespie, Rey L., 1952 (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - Gilmore, Gordon, 1955 (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - Gilpatric, Roswell, 1947-1963 (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - Gimbel, Bernard F., 1939-1966 (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - Giuganino, A., 1953 (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - Giustiniani, Piero, 1958 (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - Gladwyn, Lord, 1961 (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - Goddard, Governor Samuel P., 1966 (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - Goldblatt, Noel, 1953 (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - Goldsborough, Laird S., 1945 (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - Goldschmidt, Jakob, 1940 (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - Goldsmith, Mrs. Harold S. (folder 1 of 2), 1947-1964 (Box 121, Folder 1)
      Includes a brochure with sheet music for the song "Vote for Nixon," and a brochure for the Civil War Hall of Fame.
    - Goldsmith, Mrs. Harold S. (folder 2 of 2), 1969 (Box 121, Folder 1)
      Includes a 45 rpm phonograph record titled "Nixon Victory Song." Words and music by Leonard Keller.
    - Goldstein, Nathaniel L., 1952 (Box 121, Folder 1)
      Includes an issue of the publication The ADL Bulletin from the Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith.
    - Goldwater, Barry, 1960-1966 (Box 121, Folder 1)
      Includes the memorandum "The Significance of the Goldwater Nomination." Correspondence from Goldwater consists of copies.
    - Goldwyn, Samuel, 1944-1962 (Box 121, Folder 1)
      Includes a typescript copy of a letter from Goldwyn to General Dwight D. Eisenhower, and carbon copies of letters to Senator Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr., and Arthur Krock.
    - Golfarelli, Sigmund, 1955 (Box 121, Folder 1)
    - Goodbody, John C., 1962-1965 (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Goodhart, Arthur L., 1964 (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Goodrich, Professor Carrington, 1946-1947 (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Gordon, Max, 1936-1937 (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Goren, Charles, 1958-1964 (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Gould, Kenneth M., 1935 (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Gould, Robert, 1943 (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Gowen, Albert Y., 1940-1955 (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Grace, Peter, 1962 (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Grafton, Samuel, 1944 (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Graham, Billy, 1950-1965 (Box 121, Folder 2)
      Correspondents include Reverend J. C. Pollock. Correspondence from Graham consists of copies.
    - Graham, Kay, 1963 (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Gramazio, Ernesto, 1955-1956 (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Grandi, Dino, 1955-1958 (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Grant, Reverend W. Harvey, 1944 (Box 121, Folder 3)
    - Gray, H. E., 1953 (Box 121, Folder 3)
    - Graves, Paul H., 1940 (Box 121, Folder 3)
      Includes a draft for an untitled speech on foreign affairs for possible use in the 1940 presidential elections.
    - Graziadei, Ercole, 1953-1960 (Box 121, Folder 3)
      Includes a typescript copy of a letter from Graziadei to the Honorable Consul General of the American Embassy with his background and history as part of Graziadei's application for a U.S. visitor's visa.
    - Grebe, Reverend Frank, 1954-1961 (Box 121, Folder 3)
    - Gregory, Lawrence W., 1937 (Box 121, Folder 3)
    - Greiss, Franz, 1954 (Box 121, Folder 3)
    - Grew, Joseph C., 1942-1953 (Box 121, Folder 3)
    - Grewe, Wilhelm G., 1961 (Box 121, Folder 3)
    - Griffin, William V., 1935-1951 (Box 121, Folder 4)
      Includes correspondence regarding investment in the Somerset Hills Development Corp, and a memorandum to M.T. Moore regarding a stock purchase plan.
    - Griffis, Stanton, 1950-1954 (Box 121, Folder 4)
      Includes the pamphlet "The New British American Hospital: Madrid."
    - Grillo, Remigio, 1953 (Box 121, Folder 4)
    - Grimm, Peter, 1956 (Box 121, Folder 4)
    - Griswold, A. Whitney, 1950-1963 (Box 121, Folder 5)
      Includes the report of a conversation with Adelaide Walker, the pamphlet "Inaugural Address by Alfred Whitney Griswold," the report "Yale's Stake in the Residential Principle: Evidence from the British Experience," and the January 1955 issue of the Yale Alumni Magazine.
    - Griswold, Erwin N., 1958 (Box 121, Folder 5)
    - Gromyko, Andrei, 1944 (Box 121, Folder 5)
      Includes an official invitation card to the celebration of the twenty-seventh anniversary of the October Revolution to be held at the Soviet embassy.
    - Gronchi, President of Italy, 1956 (Box 121, Folder 5)
      Contains invitations, schedules, and other related materials for events in connection with President Gronchi's visit to the United States.
    - Grover, Allen, 1947-1954 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Grunwald, Mrs. Henry, 1966 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Guidi, Renato, 1955 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Gulek, Kasim, 1952-1955 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Gunther, John, 1939-1965 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Gurley, F. G., 1948 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Hadden, Crowell, circa 1932-1968 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Hadley, Hamilton, 1963 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Hadley, Morris, 1942 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Hailsham, Lord, 1957 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Hale, Mrs. Gardner, 1935 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Halifax, Rt. Hon. Viscount, 1942-1943 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Hall, Leonard W., 1957 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Hall, Reverend R. O., 1941 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Hall, William Webster, 1935 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Halle, Kay, 1960 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Halley, Rudolph, 1952 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Hamilton, Hamish, 1937-1952 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Hamilton, Jane, 1946 (Box 122, Folder 1)
      Includes a letter from Robert Carlen.
    - Hamilton, John, 1940-1947 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Hamilton, Thomas H., 1963-1965 (Box 122, Folder 2)
      Includes a schedule program for the University of Hawaii University Theatre.
    - Hamilton, Mrs. William H. (Ann), 1935 (Box 122, Folder 2)
    - Hammerstein, II Oscar, 1958-1959 (Box 122, Folder 2)
      Includes a prospectus for A World Law Poll, sponsored by The Pierce Butler, Jr. Foundation for Education in World Law, Inc.
    - Hanes, Ralph P., 1935-1960 (Box 122, Folder 2)
      Includes the essay "Our Supreme Court" by John Henry Kirby and a broadside distributed by the Southern Committee to Uphold the Constitution.
    - Hanes, John W., 1935-1945 (Box 122, Folder 2)
      Includes a press release with an abstract of a speech made by Hanes at the Women's National Republican Club.
    - Hannaford, Guy, 1959 (Box 122, Folder 2)
    - Hannigan, Steve, 1946-1948 (Box 122, Folder 2)
    - Harlan, John Marshall, 1954 (Box 122, Folder 2)
    - Harmon, Francis S., 1935-1963 (Box 122, Folder 2)
      Includes correspondence regarding Japan, and a photograph of a man presenting a vase to another man.
    - Harriman, Averell (Mr. and Mrs.), 1940-1961 (Box 122, Folder 2)
    - Harris, Erdman, 1935-1965 (Box 122, Folder 2)
    - Harrison, Earl G., 1946 (Box 122, Folder 2)
    - Harrison, Edwin D., 1966 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Harrison, George L., 1938 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Harrison, Gilbert A., 1954-1957 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Hayek, Professor F. A., 1959 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Hayes, Helen, 1953 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Harrison, Wallace K., 1939-1959 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Hart, Moss, 1939-1956 (Box 122, Folder 3)
      Includes a contract from Air Force Show, Inc. for the production of the play "Winged Victory."
    - Hart, Thomas, 1945 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Hart, William H., 1947-1951 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Hartford, Huntington, circa 1932-1968 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Hasbrook, Willard R., 1953 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Hassan, Ahmed, 1953 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Hatch, Harold A., 1946 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Hauge, Gabriel, 1959-1964 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Hawkes, A., 1945 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Hawkins, Gardiner, 1960 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Hayes, Carlton, 1944 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Hayes, Ralph, 1937-1955 (Box 122, Folder 3)
      Includes the pamphlet "All Through The Years" from The New York Community Trust.
    - Hays, Will H., 1938-1952 (Box 122, Folder 4)
      Includes Hays's speech "Keeping the Mind of the Nation Young," and a progress report from Citizenship Educational Service, Inc.
    - Hayward, Leland, 1943 (Box 122, Folder 4)
    - Healy, George W., 1953 (Box 122, Folder 4)
    - Heard, Gerald (and Michael Barrie), 1960-1966 (Box 122, Folder 4)
    - Heath, Donald R., 1956-1961 (Box 122, Folder 4)
    - Heathcote-Amory, Derick, 1957-1961 (Box 122, Folder 4)
    - Heffelfinger, Mary Jane (Clark), 1946-1955 (Box 122, Folder 5)
      Includes a photograph of the painting "Path On a Pond" by Jacob Ruisdael.
    - Heffelfinger, F. Peavey and Elizabeth (folder 1 of 2), 1935-1950 (Box 123, Folder 1)
      Includes brochures from the National Tax Equality Association.
    - Heffelfinger, F. Peavey and Elizabeth (folder 2 of 2), 1951-1966 (Box 123, Folder 2)
      Includes a form letter from the Republican National Finance Committee to its members, a small printed card listing Republican accomplishments to 1 July 1954, a photograph of Heffelfinger holding a copy of SPORTS ILLUSTRATED next to a man wearing a NEWSWEEK apron, and a photograph of HRL and Heffelfinger laughing.
    - Heinold, George, 1955-1956 (Box 122, Folder 5)
    - Heinz, 2nd H. J., 1938-1958 (Box 122, Folder 5)
    - Heiskell, Andrew, 1965 (Box 122, Folder 5)
    - Heller, Robert, 1947-1948 (Box 122, Folder 5)
    - Hellman, Lillian, 1936-1939 (Box 122, Folder 5)
      Includes an unsigned petition titled "Declaration of Democratic Independence to the President and the Congress of the United States of America" from the Hollywood Committee of 56.
    - Helm, Harold, 1962-1963 (Box 122, Folder 5)
    - Hemingway, Stuart, 1935-1957 (Box 122, Folder 5)
    - Henderson, L., 1947 (Box 122, Folder 5)
    - Henkel, Jost, 1953-1961 (Box 122, Folder 5)
    - Henry, M. Jules, 1939 (Box 122, Folder 5)
    - Herod, William R., 1946-1959 (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - Hersey, John, 1939-1966 (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - Herter, Christian A., 1943-1962 (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - Hibbard, David S., 1954 (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - High, Stanley, 1941-1951 (Box 123, Folder 3)
      Includes High's article "Religion: The Issue and the Answer."
    - Hill, Isabel and John C., 1946-1947 (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - Hilles, Frederick, 1939 (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - Hilton, Conrad, 1953-1955 (Box 123, Folder 3)
      Includes a pamphlet with Hilton's speech "The America I'd Like to Live In" and an annual Hilton Hotels report.
    - Hincks, John M., 1938-1966 (Box 123, Folder 4)
      Includes a letter from Frank T. Heffelfinger, and a postcard from The Hotchkiss School with a view over a golf course.
    - Hines, Betty, 1955 (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - Hobby, Oveta Culp (Mr. and Mrs.), 1942-1963 (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - Hobson, Bishop Henry W., 1938-1949 (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - Hobson, Thayer, 1935-1965 (Box 123, Folder 4)
      Includes an audit report for the William Morrow and Company, Inc. done by C. W. Heaton and Company.
    - Hochschild, Walter, 1959 (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - Hocking, William Ernest, 1943-1966 (Box 123, Folder 5)
      Includes comments made by Hocking on HRL's draft speech for the Connecticut Bar Association on justice and law, a congressional bill with a letter from Albert Lee asking to amend a part of the Chinese Exclusion Laws, an issue of the publication Post War World from the Commission on a Just and Durable Peace, the pamphlet "A Message to the Churches From the National Study Conference on the Churches and a Just and Durable Peace," a photograph of Agnes Hocking in the backyard of Kasteel Oud-Wassenaar, a photograph of Agnes Hocking with a farmer inspecting shrubbery, and the article "Principles of Mass Communication by Radio and Television from the Angle of Philosophy and Psychology."
    - Hoffman, Paul G., 1939-1966 (Box 124, Folder 1)
      Includes page proofs for Hoffman's speech "Let's LIVE for America," the speech "The World on Your Shoulders," long papers with statements made by the Research Committee of The Committee for Economic Development titled "Articles of Faith" and "Toward More Jobs and More Freedom," a confidential memorandum "How to Win the Cold War," and a folder with photographs and printed materials from the Automotive Safety Foundation Dinner honoring Paul G. Hoffman and Alexander Fraser.
    - Hofer, Philip, 1942-1943 (Box 124, Folder 2)
      Includes the "Report on the Early Stages of the Trade Union Fellowship Project."
    - Hogan, William J., 1953 (Box 124, Folder 2)
    - Hoggson, Maclean, 1935-1958 (Box 124, Folder 2)